General Manuscripts Miscellaneous Collection, 1502-2012: Finding Aid C0140
Manuscripts Division
- Ruedas, Jerónimo de, and Others, Report to King Charles III of Spain on Indigenous Revolutionary Movements in South America, 1781 June 15; Ruedas, Jerónimo de; 1 folder (Box B-001555, Folder 6)
  The report's authors and signatories include Jerónimo de Ruedas, Juan de Dios Calvo y Antequera, Pedro Antonio Cernadas y Bermúdez, Alonso Gonzáles Pérez, Manuel García de la Plata, Lorenzo Blanco y Cicerón, and Juan del Pino Manrique. Writing from the colonial Viceroyalty of the Río de la Plata (now the nations of Argentina, Chile, Bolivia, Paraguay and Uruguay), the authors cite Spanish colonial policy and taxation, as well as the ongoing revolution against the British Empire in North America, as significant influences on Indigenous revolutionary movements in Peru and elsewhere in South America.
  The report recounts events leading up to Indigenous liberation movements in the 1770s and 1780s, including the abusive administration of the Corregidor of Chayanta, which led Tomás Katari to travel to Buenos Aires in 1778 to air his people's grievances to the Spanish authorities, as well as Katari's arrest and execution and the rebellion that followed. The authors also discuss at length the rebellion led by Túpac Amaru II and the violent Spanish attempts to suppress it. They also write about the circulation of revolutionary pamphlets by Indigenous organizers in the city of La Paz, Bolivia, as a means of building support for a revolution against Spanish colonizers.
  Río de la Plata (Viceroyalty) -- History -- 18th century; Peru -- History -- Insurrection of Tupac Amaru, 1780-1781 -- Sources; La Paz (Bolivia) -- History -- Siege, 1781 -- Sources; Revolutionaries -- South America -- History -- 18th century -- Sources; Charles III, King of Spain, 1716-1788; Túpac Amaru, José Gabriel, 1738-1781; Katari María, Tomás, approximately 1740-1781
- Rumford, Benjamin Thompson, Count von., 1753-1814, 1802; 1 box (Box 42)
  ALS to Citoyen Parmentier, 26 July 1802. AM 14026
- Rummage, Patricia Newman, 1986; 1 box (Box 42)
  ALS to John T. McCutcheon, describing Scottie, F. Scott Fitzgerald's daughter, from their days as classmates at the Ethel Walker School, 11 July 1986. AM 87-62
- Rundle, Ursula, 1717; 1 box (Box 42)
  DS with Humphrey Mill, bond to Mary and Frances Hooper, 18 November 1717. AM 1524 Pyne-Henry
- Rusden, George William, 1819-1903, 1883; 1 box (Box 42)
  ALS to Dalton, sending his History of Australia and enclosing "a couple of letters about Mr. Bryce," 24 November 1883. AM 11252
- Rush, Richard, 1780-1859, Letter to Daniel Webster, 1782-1852, 1851 January 29; 1 box (Box 42)
  AM 2017-86
  Six-page letter (ALS) from American statesman Richard Rush to Daniel Webster, Secretary of State for President Millard Fillmore, regarding the Monroe Doctrine. The letter, which is addressed from Sydenham, near Philadelphia, mentions the Austro-Hungarian question, comparing Daniel Webster's foreign policy to the initial days after the proclamation of the Monroe Doctrine, as well as "Red Republicans" and Socialists in France and other diplomatic matters.
- Rushton, Peters, 1915-1949, 1947-1948; 1 box (Box 42)
  ALS, CS, and 4 ACsS to Rushton, 1947-1948; printed card, invitation to lecture, n.d.; TMs, n.d. AM 14215
- Rusling, James Fowler, 1834-1918, 1867; 1 box (Box 42)
  2 ALsS from General J. Gregg, 4 and 30 June, 1867; ALS from Captain G. E. Smith, 27 June 1867; copy of newspaper clipping, n.d. WA 1994-94
- Russell, Andrew J., Photograph of Zion's Cooperative Mercantile Institution, Salt Lake City, circa 1868; Russell, Andrew J.; 1 folder (Box P-000151, Folder 1)
  Consists of a mounted albumen photograph (8.5 x 11") by Andrew J. Russell depicting Zion's Co-operative Mercantile Institution in Salt Lake City, Utah Territory. Zion's Co-operative Mercantile Institution (ZCMI) was a department store chain founded by Mormon leader Brigham Young (1801-1877). The Cotton Yarn Depot, Eldredge and Clawson, and The Old Constitution buildings are also pictured, as are a number of people, covered wagons, and horses.
  AM 2021-33
  Purchased from Back of Beyond Books in 2020.
  Mormons -- Utah -- Salt Lake City -- History -- 19th century.; Salt Lake City (Utah) -- Buildings, structures, etc. -- Photographs.; Photographs -- 19th century.; Zion's Co-operative Mercantile Institution
- Russell, Benjamin, 1761-1845, 1788; 1 box (Box 42)
  ALS to George Thatcher, 20 August 1788. AM 22077
- Russell, Charles Edward, 1860-1941, 1921; 1 box (Box 42)
  Copy of TLS to Mrs. Lacy, 11 February 1921. AM 17847
- Russell, John, 1919-2008, 1971-1982; 1 box (Box 42)
  ACS, ALS, and 2 TLsS to William Krauss, 1971-1982; TL (carbon) from Krauss, 1972. AM 1995-69
- Russell, John, Earl Russell, 1792-1878, 1870; 1 box (Box 42)
  ALS to Samos, 1 August 1870; copy of engraving, n.d. AM 18565
- Russell, John, Earl Russell, 1792-1878, 1864; 1 box (Box 42)
  ALS to Victoria, Queen of England, recommending Hemans, son of Felicia Hemans, for Consul at Buffalo, 20 June 1864. AM 11396
- Russell, William Clark, 1844-1911, 1902; 1 box (Box 42)
  ALS to "Dear Madam," 28 March 1902. AM 20392
- Russia, Foreign Office, 1846; 1 box (Box 42)
  DS, passport, Edward E. Rankin, St. Petersburg, 2 July 1846. AM 14512
- Russia, Foreign Office, 1909; 1 box (Box 42)
  TMs, Russo-Chinese agreement regarding lands of the Chinese Eastern Railway, 10 May 1909. AM 14243
- Russia, 1793; 1 box (Box 42)
  DS, 1793. AM 13973
- Rutherford, John, 1778; 1 box (Box 42)
  ALS to Thomas Cadell, the elder, London publisher, concerning his Cicero, 16 February 1778. AM 80-70
- Rutherford, William Grimson, 1891; 1 box (Box 42)
  ALS to General Terry, 15 December 1891. Removed from book
- Rutledge, John, 1739-1800, 1776-1780; 1 box (Box 42)
  ALS to Lincoln, 11 July 1779; ALS to Rop, 4 November 1781; ALS to Sir Salway, 24 March 1776; 3 copies of engravings, n.d. AM 18565
- Saclier, Jean-Philippe, Speech about the French Revolution and the Abolition of Slavery, 1795; 1 box (Box 43)
  Consists of a seven-page manuscript speech addressed to the commune of Charolles, France, by Jean-Philippe Saclier, a lawyer in the Parliament of Burgundy, in which he argues for the abolition of slavery. In the rest of the speech, Saclier welcomes the fall of Maximilien Robespierre and the establishment of a new republican government; urges for citizens to exercise new rights they gained during the French Revolution; and extols the value of freedom of the press.
  AM 2020-23
  Purchased from Librairie Nicolas Malais in 2019.
  Abolitionists -- France -- History -- 18th century.; France -- History -- Revolution, 1789-1799.
- Sadlier, Michael, 1888-1957, 1936; 1 box (Box 43)
  ALS to Carroll A. Wilson, 20 March 1936. AM 20699
- St. John Harbour, 1800; 1 box (Box 43)
  D, nautical chart of St. John Harbour, ca. 1800. AM 84-36
- St. Leon, Dufresne, 1791; 1 box (Box 43)
  ALS to "Monsieur" thanking him for warning concerning visit of Sr. Thevenot, 28 February 1791. AM 13257
- Sainte-Beuve, Charles Augustin, 1804-1869, undated; 1 box (Box 43)
  ALS, in French, to Victor Hugo expressing his thanks for Cromwell, and mentioning Keats, n.d. AM 81-12
- Saintsbury, George Edward Bateman, 1845-1933, undated; 1 box (Box 43)
  Autograph signature, n.d. AM 16414
- Salisbury, Robert Arthur Talbot Gascoyne Cecil, Marquis of, 1830-1903, 1870-1873; 1 box (Box 43)
  ALS to W. Marden, 23 May 1873; ALS to S. C. Hall, 14 June 1870; copy of engraving, n.d. AM 18565
- Salomon-Calor, Wilhelm, 1927; 1 box (Box 43)
  TLS, in German, to W. B. Scott thanking him for sending a copy of his book, 10 May 1927. AM 12513
- Salt, Henry Stephens, 1851-1939, 1891; 1 box (Box 43)
  ALS to Elkin Mathews, 10 August 1891. AM 19713
- Salter, James, b. 1925, 1988-1996; 1 box (Box 43)
  Correspondence with William Drenttel, 8 letters, 1988-1996. AM 1998-99
- Salinger, J. D., 1919-2010, 1951 August 24; 1 box (Box 43A)
  AM 2013-114
  TLS to Katherine Biggins Magill, relating to Catcher in the Rye, 1 letter. Restriction: not to be photocopied.
- Salinger, J. D., 1919-2010, 1964; 1 box (Box 43)
  TLS to Bertram Mills, guidance director Mascoma Valley Regional High School West Canaan, NH, 11 November 1964. Restriction: not to be photocopied. AM 88-17
- Saltus, Edgar Everton, 1855-1921, undated; 1 box (Box 43)
  ALS to J. W. Black, n.d. AM 14768
- Sanborn, Franklin Benjamin, 1831-1917, 1876; 1 box (Box 43)
  ALS to Mr. Bowles regarding an appointment to be made, 23 May 1876. AM 11822
- Sanders, Lewis, 1854; 1 box (Box 43)
  ALS to Jefferson Davis, concerning squatters and the U.S. Land Commission, 28 January 1854. AM 8713
- Santa Anna, Antonio Lopez de, 1794-1876, 1832-1847; 1 box (Box 43)
  Photostat of ALS to Lopez, 22 February 1847; ADS, in Spanish, signed by Lopez, 20 December 1832. AM 17484
- Santayana, George, 1863-1952, 1949; 1 box (Box 43)
  ALS to Mr. Allison Delarue, 24 May 1949. AM 15662
- Sarduy, Severo, 1937-1993, 1983-2000; 1 box (Box 43)
  AMs, notes by Sarduy, 1983-1984; TLS from Edgardo Moctezuma to Peter Johnson, 2 August 2000. AM 2001-25
- Sargent, John Singer, 1856-1925, 1903; 1 box (Box 43)
  ALS to John Lambert, 5 March 1903. AM 13240
- Sargent, Redford W, 1949; 1 box (Box 43)
  7 items related to the Russian Famine Voyange, some dated 1949. AM 2006-40
- Saroyan, William, 1908-1981, 1951; 1 box (Box 43)
  ANS on printed page of "The Father," 21 January 1951. AM 17995
- Saroyan, William, 1908-1981, 1938; 1 box (Box 43)
  DS, endorsed check also signed by Robert Grabhorn, 18 May 1938. Transferred from Graphic Arts, 10/2009. See record for Seroyan's "A Christmas Psalm" (1935)
- Sartre, Jean-Paul, 1905-1980, 1963; 1 box (Box 43)
  TLS to Robert F. Goheen, regretting that he will not be able to lecture at Princeton the next year, 12 March 1963. AM 17582
- Saunderrock, Phillip, 1704; 1 box (Box 43)
  DS to Hugh Sloggett, receipt of money for the relief of the poor of the parish Jacobstow, Devon, 20 November 1704. AM 1530 Pyne Henry
- Savage, Henry L, undated; 1 box (Box 43)
  "Life of Dr. Witherspoon," AMs (Xerox), n.d. AM 21628
- Savage, Henry Lyttleton, Class of 1915, undated; 1 box (Box 43)
  "The Arte of Angling," AMs, notes, n.d.
- Savage, Henry Lyttleton, Class of 1915, 1940; 1 box (Box 43)
  ALS to Professor Lawrence Thompson concerning the coming of Elmer Adler to Princeton, 28 September 1940. AM 77-105
- Savery, William E., b. 1842, 1859; 1 box (Box 43)
  11 ALsS to his parents during his travel in Europe, 7 April - 20 July 1859. AM 2005-141
- Savile, Harold, 1933; 1 box (Box 43)
  TLS to Harriet Hulse, 14 August 1933. AM 92-62
- Sawyer, Philip, 1889; 1 box (Box 43)
  2 ALsS to Benjamin Hamblin, 1 March and 1 April 1889. AM 19136
- Saxe, John Godfrey, 1816-1887, 1870-1879; 1 box (Box 43)
  ALS to Wickle, 1 October 1879; "Somewhere," AMsS, poem, 9 February 1871; autograph signature, 9 December 1870. AM 9943
- Saxton, Charles, 1796; 1 box (Box 43)
  DS to John Pelton, quit claims, 7 January 1796. AM 1924
- Sayre, Lewis A., 1820-1900, 1878; 1 box (Box 43)
  ALS to Mr. Elmer, M.D., 24 June 1878. AM 16232
- Sayre, Paul T., Class of 1840, 1886; 1 box (Box 43)
  ALS to Moses Taylor Pyne regarding the life and character of Joseph Henry, 20 July 1886. AM 160 Pyne Henry
- Sayre, Stephen, 1736-1818, 1811; 1 box (Box 43)
  DS, agreement in which Andrew Hunter apprentices a negro woman, Celia Freeman, to Sayre for 7 years to be taught housewifery, 30 May 1811. AM 9162
- Schaff, Philip, 1819-1893, 1844; 1 box (Box 43)
  ALS to James W. Alexander, class of 1820, in German, 4 September 1844. AM 2003
- Schaff, Morris, 1840-1929, 1909; 1 box (Box 43)
  TLS to Alfred A. Woodhull discussing some of Schaff's writings, 22 June 1909. AM 9104
- Schauseil, Theodore, Watercolor Painting of the Cheyenne and Arapaho Mission School, Darlington Agency, circa 1875; Schauseil, Theodore, 1838-1920; 1 folder (Box P-000151, Folder 3)
  Purchased from William Reese Company in 2021 (AM 2022-010).
  Consists of a watercolor painting by German-American artist Theodore Schauseil (1838-1920) titled "Mission of the Chey. and Arap. Agency. Built in the Year 1875." The painting depicts the Cheyenne and Arapaho Mission School at the Darlington Agency in what was then referred to as Indian Territory, now Oklahoma. The boarding school was built by Orthodox Quakers with United States government funds in 1872 as part of an assimilationist effort by white settlers to suppress Indigenous American peoples, cultures and languages. The painting reflects changes made to the school in 1875 to separate Cheyenne and Arapaho children. In 1879, the school was renamed the Arapaho Manual Labor and Boarding School, and Cheyenne students were moved to the Cheyenne Manual Labor and Boarding School at Caddo Springs.
  Schauseil
  Theodore Schauseil (1838-1920) was a German-American artist who was a scout in the 4th United States Cavalry at Fort Sill beginning in 1874. During this time, he worked as an interpreter and draftsman.
  Off-reservation boarding schools -- Oklahoma; Quakers -- Oklahoma -- History -- 19th century -- Sources; Watercolors (paintings) -- 19th century; Cheyenne and Arapaho Tribes, Oklahoma
- Scheil, Dennis E., b. 1954, 1979; 1 box (Box 58)
  "A Pome," AMsS writte on oversize folder of Joesph Shippen, 6 February 1979. AM 79-0
- Schenck, Ferdinand Shureman, 1790-1860, 1833; 1 box (Box 43)
  ALS to "The Editor of the Globe," 5 December 1833. AM 12716
- Schlegel, August Wilhelm von, 1767-1895, 1814; 1 box (Box 43)
  ALS to unknown recipient, 1814. AM 14564
- Schnopp, Karl, 1933; 1 box (Box 43)
  ALS to Gauleiter Julius Streicher, 13 May 1933. AM 19596
- Schoeck, Richard Joseph, 1920-2008, 1939-1961; 1 box (Box 43)
  TLS from Olin Downes, 4 November 1939; TLS from H. L. Mencken, 7 August 1946; ALS from Robert Nathan, n.d.; TLS from Howard R. Patch, 15 March 1961; ALS from C. S. Lewis, 14 March 1961. AM 18895
- Schofield, Ernest L, 1919-1978; 1 box (Box 43)
  Citations, brochures, and bulletins, all Xeroxes of originals at the U. S. Veterans Medical Center, Lyons, NJ, 1919-1978. AM 88-65
- Schofield, John McAllister, 1831-1906, 1862; 1 box (Box 43)
  Photostat of ALS to "Colonel," 16 June 1862. AM 17484
- Schoolcraft, Henry Rowe, 1793-1864, 1831; 1 box (Box 43)
  ALS to Dr. John Torrey, 29 October 1831. AM 15631
- Schroeder, John F., Class of 1819, 1819-1823; 1 box (Box 43)
  2 copies of DsS, 1819-1823. AM 7699, 7700
- Schroeder, Nathan Southwick, Class of 1898, 1917-1919; 1 box (Box 43)
  "Final Report of the Bureau of State Organizations of the United States Fuel Administration," TMs, 1917-1919. AM 16658
- Schurman, Jacob Gould, 1854-1942, 1907; 1 box (Box 43)
  TLS to H. W. Grove, 14 May 1907. AM 15296
- Schuyler, Philip, 1733-1804, undated; 1 box (Box 43)
  ALS to Robert Morris concerning Indian supplies, n.d. AM 13070
- Schweitzer, Albert, 1875-1965, 1949-1955; 1 box (Box 43)
  ALS from Helene Schweitzer to Ann Clark, 13 March 1950; printed invitation to Clark, 17 July 1949; TLS (carbon) from Emery Ross to Helene Schweitzer with handwritten lines, 21 August 1950; ALS to Mr. and Mrs. Clark, thanking them, 28 June 1955. AM 80-92
- Schwerdt, C. F. G. R., 1872-1945, 1928-1935; 1 box (Box 43)
  2 TLsS and 1 ALS to Harry Worcester Smith, 1928-1929; 2 TLs (carbon) and 1 CS from Smith, 1929-1935. AM 92-9
- Scollard, Clinton, 1860-1932, 1904-1908; 1 box (Box 44)
  2 ALsS to Francis J. Dicks, 24 April 1904 and 7 May 1908. AM 12880
- Scott, David, 1817; 1 box (Box 44)
  ALS to Artemus Boies inviting him to Harrisburgh and giving an account of travel facilities from Princeton, 18 June 1817. AM 13472
- Scott, Jack, 1967; 1 box (Box 44)
  "From Dissenter to Revolutionary: The Metamorphosis of John Witherspoon," TMs (Xerox), c. 1967. AM 19250
- Scott, John Turnbull, Class of 1845, 1865; 1 box (Box 44)
  ALS to Buhler, 28 June 1865; obituary, n.d. AM 14426
- Scott, Samuel, 1856; 1 box (Box 44)
  DS to William McHenry Scott, deed for land in Hamilton Co. Ohio, 10 July 1856. AM 11010
- Scott, Walter, 1886-1911; 1 box (Box 44)
  23 ALsS, 2 ANsS, 1 AL, and 1 AN from various correspondents to Scott and Will H. Dircks, publishers, 1886-1911. AM 1997-23
- Scott, William, 1851; 1 box (Box 44)
  DS, copy of last Will and Testament, 5 June 1851. AM 11011
- Scott, William Berryman, 1858-1947, 1901-1940; 1 box (Box 58)
  Illuminated birthday card, Ms, 1928; 14 certificates for various accomplishments, 1901-1940
- Scott, Winfield, 1786-1866, 1836-1861; 1 box (Box 44)
  DS to Mrs. Col. Davies, pass to the U. S. lines, 25 October, 1861; ALS to Captain R. Anderson, 8 April 1843; Photostat of ALS to Major Graham, 17 February 1846; Photostat of ALS to "Sir," 23 May 1836. AM 17484, 17723, 21824
- Scribner, W. O, 1866; 1 box (Box 44)
  ALS to Vaola J. Hartshorn giving an account of his personal history in connection with the U. S. Civil War, 5 February 1866. AM 11026
- Scudder, Horace Elisha, 1838-1902, 1896; 1 box (Box 44)
  ALS to William Libbey accepting invitation to the sesquicentennial celebration of Princeton University, 9 October 1896. AM 9946
- Scudder, John, 1793-1855, 1848; 1 box (Box 44)
  ALS to John Maclean about missionary life in India, 23 February 1848. AM 2317
- Scudder, John, 1759-1836, 1813; 1 box (Box 44)
  ALS to Thomas P. Johnson with reference to the suit of the Executor of Leffert's estate, 5 April 1813. AM 10560
- Scudder, Nathaniel, 1733-1781, 1777; 1 box (Box 44)
  ALS, with typed transcript, to "Sir," 28 March 1777; printed poem by Benjamin Prime on Scudder's death, 1781. AM 19612
- Seaton, William W., 1765-1866, undated; 1 box (Box 44)
  ALS to "Dear Sir," n.d. AM 12665
- Sedgwick, Adam, 1785-1873, undated; 1 box (Box 44)
  AMs, notes for lecture, n.d. AM 8025
- Sedgwick, Catharine Maria, 1789-1867, 1837; 1 box (Box 44)
  ALS to Lewis J. Ceist, thank-you note, 4 June 1837. AM 80-79
- Sedgwick, Catharine Maria, 1789-1867, 1851-1854; 1 box (Box 44)
  ALS to G. P. Putnam, 20 February 1854; 2 autograph signatures, 1 dated 9 August 1851, 1 n.d. AM 1996-16
- Sedgwick, Charles, 1870; 1 box (Box 44)
  ALS to his family, 1870. AM 12700
- Sedgwick, Theodore, 1811-1859, 1827-1837; 1 box (Box 44)
  ALS to "Dear Sir" regarding his aunt, Catharine Maria Sedgwick, 18 June 1827; 2 ALsS to Col. Aspinwall regarding Sedgwick, 1837. AM 1996-78
- Seely, Elias P., 1791-1846, 1816; 1 box (Box 44)
  ADS to James Lee, receipt for judgment bond, 9 September 1816. AM 961 Lee
- Selina, Countess of Huntingdon, 1707-1791, undated; 1 box (Box 44)
  Typewritten extractions from "Life and times of Selina, Countess of Huntingdon," and "Memorials of the Right Hon. Selina, Countess of Huntingdon," n.d. AM 2018, 2019 Pyne-Henry
- Selous, Frederick Courteney, 1851-1917, 1893-1925; 1 box (Box 44)
  ALS to Mr. Colles, 28 September 1893; photograph of Selous's old house, 1925. AM 21796
- Selous, Frederick Courteney, 1851-1917, 1897; 1 box (Box 44)
  ALS to "My Dear Sir" commenting on his visit to the Rocky Mountains and hoping to meet with him, 4 March 1897. AM 90-59
- Selva, Salomón de la, 1893-1959, undated; 1 box (Box 44)
  22 AMss and 2 TMss, poems, n.d. AM 20919
- Senghor, Léopold Sédar, 1906-2001, 1958; 1 box (Box 44)
  TLS to François Hoffmann, in French, 27 June 1958. AM 2001-87
- Servais, François, 1847-1901, undated; 1 box (Box 44)
  ALS to Monsieur Servais, n.d. AM 2002-135
- Servis, Jacob, 1837; 1 box (Box 44)
  DS, agreement for sale of property with Hohn Golden, 16 January 1837. AM 1838
- Seton, Ernest Thompson, 1860-1946, 1899; 1 box (Box 44)
  2 photographs of captured wolves, n.d.; photograph of Seton with printed signature, n.d.; copy of ALS to Mrs. Milbank, 1 June 1899. AM 13834
- Seward, Frederick W., 1830-1915, 1861; 1 box (Box 44)
  ALS to E. A. Stansbury 29 April 1861. AM 12716
- Seward, William Henry Jr., 1839-1920, 1885; 1 box (Box 44)
  ALS to Mrs. Martin discussing a Chinese exhibit, 18 March 1885. AM 22077
- Seward, William Henry, 1801-1872, 1849; 1 box (Box 44)
  ALS to David A. Hall about securing a house in Washington D. C., 4 August 1849. AM 9302
- Seward, William Henry, 1801-1872, 1850; 1 box (Box 44)
  ALS to James Johonnet regretting that he could not meet the Friends of Free Education at Syracuse, 7 January 1850. AM 10565 Pyne Henry
- Seward, William Henry, 1801-1872, 1862-1868; 1 box (Box 44)
  ALS to "Sir," 7 March 1862; ALS to Judson Kilpatrick, 27 March 1868. AM 17726
- Seward, William Henry, 1801-1872, undated; 1 box (Box 44)
  Autograph signature on envelope addressed to L. B. Prince, n.d. AM 9287
- Seward, William Henry, 1801-1872, 1860; 1 box (Box 44)
  ALS to Charles Cullis, 23 February 1860. AM 12716
- Sewers, James, 1826; 1 box (Box 44)
  "Wyoming," AMs, poem, n.d.; "Greece," AMs, poem, 1826. AM 8213, 8214 Hart
- Seymour, Charles, 1885-1963, 1931; 1 box (Box 44)
  TLS to William Halleran, 23 February 1931. AM 12390
- Shadwell, Thomas, 1642-1692, 1673; 1 box (Box 44)
  DS, 16 April 1673. AM 21354
- Shahn, Ben, 1898-1969, 1957; 1 box (Box 44)
  Copy of TL to "Dear Lane," 30 November 1957. AM 83-145
- Shaler, Alexander, 1827-1911, 1886; 1 box (Box 44)
  ALS to General Horatio C. King regarding testifying on Shaler's behalf, 22 April 1886. AM 92-62
- Shannon, Chalres H, 1904; 1 box (Box 44)
  ALS to Lady Gregory, 9 May 1904. AM 14788
- Shannon, Isaac, 1847; 1 box (Box 44)
  Photostat of D, financial statement for first year at the Princeton Theological Seminary, 1847. AM 12501
- Sharp, William, Engraving of Joseph Johnson, undated; Sharp, William, 1749-1824; 1 box (Box 44)
  Engraving of bookseller and publisher Joseph Johnson (1738-1809) by engraver and artist William Sharp (1749-1824) from a portrait by Moses Haughton.
  Annotation on the print notes that it had been in the possession of John Miles.
  AM 19742
  Gift of Charles Ryskamp in 1968.
- Shaw, Anna Howard, 1847-1919, 1911; 1 box (Box 44)
  TLS to Mrs. Fiske regarding the suffrage movement, 29 August 1911. AM 16283
- Shaw, Josiah, 1820; 1 box (Box 44)
  ADS, certifying Sally Adams as a member of the Methodist Society, 19 November 1820. AM 2004-128
- Shaw, Julia, 1943; 1 box (Box 44)
  ALS to Parke E. Doland about the death of her mother, 3 February 1943. AM 13475
- Shaw, Lemuel, 1781-1861, 1856; 1 box (Box 44)
  ALS to "My Dear Sir," 1 August 1856. AM 20891
- Shaw, Samuel, Jr, 1767; 1 box (Box 44)
  ALS to Jonathan Sergeant in regard to "debts collected," 31 October 1767. AM 431 Pyne Henry
- Shea, J. B, 1914; 1 box (Box 44)
  TLS to V. L. Collins about journal of Colonel George Morgan. AM 9795
- Shearer, George Lewis, 1835-1919, 1862; 1 box (Box 44)
  Anonymous AL demonstrating intense racism in Washington D. C., 1862. AM 19733
- Sheffey, Hugh W., 1815-1889, 1862; 1 box (Box 44)
  ALS to Hon. Thomas S. Bocock, 31 March 1862. AM 13365
- Sheffield, Noel D, 1945; 1 box (Box 44)
  TLS to Logan Pearsall Smith regarding "phrasal collocations," 19 February 1945. AM 22077
- Sheldon, Edward Wright, 1858-1934, 1875-1898; 1 box (Box 44)
  2 photographs of Santiago Bay with AN on back, 1898; 2 photographs of unidentified bay, 1875. AM 1995-41
- Sheldon, Elisha, 1709-1779, undated; 1 box (Box 44)
  Photostat of DS, roll of field staff and commissioned officers, n.d. AM 10015
- Sherburne, Henry, Class of 1759, 1 box (Box 45)
  DS to Jonathan Sergeant, receipt, signed by Thomas Watson, 26 June 1759. AM 474 Pyne Henry
- Sheridan, Philip Henry, 1831-1888, 1872; 1 box (Box 45)
  Photostat of ALS to unknown recipient, 23 December 1872. AM 17484
- Sherman, Frank Dempster, 1860-1916, undated; 1 box (Box 45)
  "A May Morning," copy of AMsS, poem, n.d. AM 17606
- Sherman, Frank Dempster, 1860-1916, undated; 1 box (Box 45)
  "Nantucket," facsimile of AMsS, poem, n.d. Removed from F. D. Sherman's "Lyrics for a lute," 1890. EX PS2812. L8. 1890. AM 22077
- Sherman, James L., Civil War Letter and Other Correspondence to Mary Pearl, 1854-1864; Sherman, James L., 1839-1900; 1 folder (Box B-001748, Folder 5)